# **Bianca Martinez**

# **Quality Inspector - Filconn Inc**

Maricopa, AZ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Bianca-Martinez/d8dc5a3d8a86aa8d

Quality Inspector with over seven years of experience, and areas of expertise include In-Process Inspection, Final Inspection, and First Piece buy off, First Article, Hardness Testing, Assembly Inspection, and Pre - Plate/ After - Plate, Blueprint understanding, and Looking for a company that prides itself on a strong work ethic, and with an emphasis surrounding professionalism to provide sustainability for personal, and professional growth. Become an exceptional employee, be truthful to others, and myself, and having integrity and a good work ethic. Recognize that true success is a balance between personal success, and success of the company. If your company hires me I will demonstrate all those components.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Quality Inspector**

Filconn Inc - Chandler, AZ - 2014 to Present

- \* Skilled in reading and interpreting engineered drawings.
- \* Capable to work independently with little supervision.
- \* Effective communication skills, written and verbal.
- \* Capable to read, interpret, and follow SOPs, labels, instructions, specifications, reference materials.
- \* Ability to read, and interpret, and communicate technical information.
- \* Able to operate specific equipment and instrumentation necessary to fulfill job responsibilities.
- \* Skilled with computers and data collection hardware and software skills necessary to fulfill job responsibilities.
- \* Understand all policies and significant impact of job activities in accordance with the ISO 9001:2008 standard and an understanding of Quality Best Practices.
- $^{\star}$  Knowledgeable math skills necessary to fulfill job responsibilities.

Internal Quality Auditing training.

- \* Experienced with First Article Acceptance, Lot Acceptance, First Article Layouts, and Final Inspection.
- \* Perform dimensional verification activities per the Part Inspection Standard.
- \* Perform visual verification activities per the Part Inspection Plan.
- \* Perform 1st Piece and In-Process Inspections.
- \* Assists Operations with the documentation and handling nonconforming products.
- \* Performs Layered Process Audit (LPA) activities.
- \* Maintains a clean and orderly work environment.
- \* Documents verification activities and communicates quality plan failures (out-of-tolerance or out-of-control conditions.)
- \* Manage all gauging methods (storage, retrieval, calibration status, and physical condition) used in the Part Inspection Standard.
- \* Assist Quality Engineers in the calibration and verification of equipment.

# **Quality Inspector**

Odyssey Medical Inc - Bartlett, TN - 2013 to 2014

- \* Trained on performing finished goods audit.
- \* Use a variety of measuring instruments when required.
- \* Use field and customer feedback to improve the quality where required.
- \* Perform task of determining accuracy of orders to schedule and jobs.

- \* Make decisions as to acceptable quality within limits and print specifications and workmanship standards.
- \* Perform limited dimensional and visual inspections of purchased parts and materials for conformity to standards, specifications and processing requirements.
- \* Work closely with manufacturing, engineering, customer support.
- \* Must perform all work in accordance with safety procedures.
- \* Trained in reading and interpreting engineered drawings.
- \* Capable to work independently and as part of a team.
- \* Effective communication skills, written and verbal.
- \* Team leadership skills in a technical environment.
- \* Qualified to read, interpret, and follow SOPs, labels, instructions, specifications, reference materials.
- \* Ability to read, and interpret, and communicate technical information.
- \* Able to operate specific equipment and instrumentation necessary to fulfill job responsibilities.
- \* Skilled with computers and data collection hardware and software skills necessary to fulfill job responsibilities.
- \* Understand all policies and significant impact of job activities in accordance with the ISO 9001:2008 standard and an understanding of Quality Best Practices.
- \* Knowledgeable math skills necessary to fulfill job responsibilities.

## **CNC Machine Operator II**

Odyssey Medical Inc - Bartlett, TN - 2011 to 2013

- \* Basic operation knowledge and capable to run several different machines.
- \* Inspect product for nonconformities.
- \* Document measurements on Measurement Record Sheets.
- \* Perform only approved production runs.
- \* Stop production if nonconformity is identified.
- \* Knowledgeable of Quality Controls and the Quality System.
- \* Assist in the prevention and resolution of production issues with assigned products by working with engineering and quality personnel.
- \* Work with minimal supervision.
- \* Change tools as necessary or as required.
- \* Assist Programmers with machine setups or as needed.
- \* Make offset changes as approved by programmer or senior machinist.

## Inspector

Smith & Nephew - Memphis, TN - May 2010 to June 2011

Quality Manufacturing 1

- \* Responsible for inspection of finished and in-process products by performing visual, basic dimensional and documentation Inspection per specified procedures or instructions within the framework of FDA quality systems requirements and ISO 9001 standards.
- \* Experienced with using Measuring devices, Calipers, micrometer, Micro View, CMM.
- \* Great productivity daily.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor's of Information and Technology**

University of Phoenix - Tempe, AZ April 2015 to Present

## GED in leadership, communication and life coping skills

Military School - Queen Creek, AZ

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

## **PROFICIENCY**

- Complete understanding of numerical control and blueprint interpretation
- Competent material handling and precise chemical processing
- Skillful in Microsoft applications and production procedures
- Experience with Quality Basic system (AS9100) and Federal Aviation Regulations

## **DEXTERITY**

- Extremely quick at learning new skills and becoming proficient
- Highly adaptable to a changing environment
- Thrives in authoritative positions with the ability to make business minded decisions

## COMMUNICATION

- Commended for excellent communication abilities shown through documentation reporting and professional emails to our vendors
- During State Inspections passed all required field tests for Quality Inspection
- · Chosen as the Quality Representative by peers to address any issues to upper management

## **LEADERSHIP**

- Appointed Lead Inspector by management
- Encouraged coworkers to maintain a high level of productivity during rush weeks
- Spearheaded outside events for employee engagement

## TIPS:

Bilingual, Exceptional in hard work, I will give my best efforts to achieve my objective that I set out to do. I never give up, and I give my best efforts to do my best to fit the qualifications of your company, and your work environment. Get along well with other; I am aware of all duties that come with a job. I am willing to do whatever I need to do to be the best employee.